# **Austin Gilmore**

## Web Developer | (919) 616-7488 | Raleigh, NC 27606

Email <u>austingilmora@gmail.com</u> | LinkedIn <u>linkedin.com/in/austin-gilmore</u>
Portfolio <u>austingilmora.github.io/austin-gilmore-portfolio/</u> | Github <u>github.com/austingilmora</u>

## **SUMMARY**

Web developer looking for a new opportunity to kickstart my coding career. With 5+ years in education, I have developed excellent planning, project management, and communication skills which I hope to integrate into a web development role.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Node, Express, mySQL, API'S, MongoDB, GraphQL, Git, Github, JQuery,

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### English Teacher | Self-employed | October 2017 - June 2021 | Remote

- Taught children age 5-14 English as a second language, including grammar, writing, science, and math
- Planned and conducted online classes remotely
- Managed individual feedback and adapted course structure to suit each child's learning needs

#### English Teacher | Chungdahm Learning Institute | July 2016 - October 2017 | Bucheon, South Korea

- Taught children age 5-14 English as a second language, ranging from phonics to essay writing and debate
- Reviewed, corrected, and graded writing homework and tests, checking for language clarity, skill, and grammar
- Led immersive English language field trips, conversing with the students while engaging them in new environments
- Adapted course structure to suit the mixed learning levels of each classroom

#### Office Management | Gilmore Construction Services | August 2015 - July 2016 | Raleigh, NC

- Planned and executed the relocation of operations from Raleigh to Boston of this family-owned startup
- Invoice generation, bank reconciliation and liaising with tax consultant
- General administrative support including managing phone calls, appointments, and customer service.

## **EDUCATION**

University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill Coding Bootcamp | *Full Stack Web Development Certificate* | March 2022 University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill *Bachelor of Arts* | Global Studies | May 2015 Freie Universität Berlin | FUBiS- Freie Universität Berlin International Summer | Summer 2014

### **PROJECTS**

**Roadie** https://github.com/Osamadahnoun/roadie | https://on-the-roadie.herokuapp.com/ MERN Social Networking application that allows travelers to post about their experiences and connect with other travelers. *Tech Utilized: React, GraphQL, MongoDB, Chakra* 

**Treaddit** https://github.com/aucoats/treaddit|https://treaddit.herokuapp.com/

An application that helps users connect to hiking trails around them and other like-minded hikers *Tech Utilized: Handlebars, Express, Node, MongoDB* 

**Saving Sense** | https://github.com/austingilmora/saving-sense | https://dry-gorge-57166.herokuapp.com/ A PWA application that helps users manage their budgets *Tech Utilized: IndexedDB, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose*